[{"question": "What are Nibble, Word and Byte in computer language.?", "option1": "A) Byte = 8 bits, Word= 4 Bytes, Nibble= 8 Bytes", "option2": "B) Byte = 8 bits, Word=2\u00a0Bytes, Nibble=4\u00a0Bytes", "option3": "C) Byte = 8 bits, Word=12 bits, Nibble=32\u00a0Bits", "option4": "D) Byte = 8 bits, Word=24\u00a0bits, Nibble=40\u00a0Bits", "ans": "B"}, {"question": "Choose correct representation of Decimal number in Binary.", "option1": "A) 0   0000\n1   0001\n2   0010\n3   0011\n4   0100\n", "option2": "B) 5   0101\n6   0110\n7   0111\n8   1000\n9   1001\n", "option3": "C) 10  1010    A\n11  1011    B\n12  1100    C\n13  1101    D  \n14  1110    E\n15  1111    F", "option4": "D) All the above", "ans": "D"}, {"question": "What is the operator used to make 1's One's compliment.?", "option1": "A) & Bitwise AND Operator", "option2": "B) | Bitwise OR operator", "option3": "C) ~ Bitwise Negate Operator", "option4": "D) ^ Bitwise Exclusive OR", "ans": "C"}, {"question": "What is the result of 0110 & 1100.?", "option1": "A) 1000", "option2": "B) 0100", "option3": "C) 0001", "option4": "D) 1010", "ans": "B"}, {"question": "What is the output of Bitwise OR operation | on (0110 | 1100).?", "option1": "A) 1110", "option2": "B) 1100", "option3": "C) 1000", "option4": "D) 1010", "ans": "A"}, {"question": "What is the output of Exclusive OR ^ operator on 0110^1000.?", "option1": "A) 1000", "option2": "B) 1110", "option3": "C) 0011", "option4": "D) 0001", "ans": "B"}, {"question": "What is the output of Left Shift Operator << on (00011000<<2).?", "option1": "A) 01100000", "option2": "B) 11000000", "option3": "C) 00000110", "option4": "D) 00000011", "ans": "A"}, {"question": "What is the result of Right Shift Operator >> on (00110000>>2).?", "option1": "A) 11000000", "option2": "B) 00001100", "option3": "C) 01100000", "option4": "D) 11001111", "ans": "B"}, {"question": "Choose correct statement about Left Shift Operator << .?", "option1": "A) Left shift operator shifts individual bits on the left side", "option2": "B) When shifting left side, overflow bits are ignored.", "option3": "C) Zeroes are filled on the right side", "option4": "D) All the above", "ans": "D"}, {"question": " Choose a correct statement about Right Shift Operator >> .?", "option1": "A) Right shift operator shift individual bits on to the right side.", "option2": "B) When shifting bits right side, overflow bits on the right are ignored or truncated.", "option3": "C) Zeroes are filled on the left side.", "option4": "D) All the above", "ans": "D"}, {"question": " What is a Single Operand Operator below.?", "option1": "A) &", "option2": "B) |", "option3": "C) ^", "option4": "D) ~", "ans": "D"}, {"question": " What is the Bitwise operator used to set\u00a0a particular bit value to 1.?", "option1": "A) & AND", "option2": "B) | OR", "option3": "C) ^ Exclusive OR", "option4": "D) ~ Operator", "ans": "B"}, {"question": " What is the Bitwise operator used set a particular bit to Zero 0.?", "option1": "A) & Operator", "option2": "B) | OR operator", "option3": "C) ^ Exclusive Operator", "option4": "D) ~ TILDE Operator", "ans": "A"}, {"question": " Which is Bit Toggling operator below.?", "option1": "A) & AND operator", "option2": "B) | OR operator", "option3": "C) ^ Exclusive Operator", "option4": "D) ~ TILDE operator", "ans": "D"}, {"question": " Which is the format specifier used to prefix 0x and print a number in hexadecimal notation.?", "option1": "A) %x", "option2": "B) %0x", "option3": "C) %#x", "option4": "D) %hx", "ans": "C"}, {"question": " Left Shift operation is equivalent to.?", "option1": "A) Division by 2", "option2": "B) Multiplying by 2", "option3": "C) Adding 2", "option4": "D) Subtracting 2", "ans": "B"}, {"question": " Right Shift operation >> is equivalent to .?", "option1": "A) Multiplying by 2", "option2": "B) Division by 2", "option3": "C) Adding 2", "option4": "D) Subtracting 2", "ans": "B"}, {"question": " What is the minimum and maximum values in Octal Number System.?", "option1": "A) 1 to 8", "option2": "B) 0 to 7", "option3": "C) 2 to 9", "option4": "D) None of the above", "ans": "B"}, {"question": " What number system is not understood by C language compiler directly.?", "option1": "A) Decimal", "option2": "B) Octal", "option3": "C) Binary", "option4": "D) Hex Decimal", "ans": "C"}, {"question": " Choose a correct statement about C Bitwise operators.?", "option1": "A) 0^number = number", "option2": "B) 1 | number = number", "option3": "C) 0 & number = 0", "option4": "D) All the above", "ans": "D"}]
